[](https://poki.com/ "Go to homepage")What are you playing today?

**Privacy Statement - UK**
==========================

#### Version July 2023

1\. Some info about us!
-----------------------

Hello there! Thanks for visiting our privacy info page. We are a company called Poki B.V. On this page, we'll explain what is done with the data collected via our website. Data such as which game you played and at what level you stopped. We also want to make sure your privacy is protected. Therefore, we'll tell you about the steps we take for that and also explain what you can do.

To make sure our website is safe and suitable for everyone, we have something called the "Privacy-Friendly Mode." When you visit our website from the UK, you enter directly in the Privacy-Friendly Mode. In this mode, we only show ads that are appropriate for all ages. The ads are non-personalized. This means that they are not selected based on any information about you. The ads are not "targeted" at you in specific. You can read more about our Privacy-Friendly Mode below!

Each section below gives you a summary of the important information using simple words. If you click on a topic you're interested in, more details will show. If you want to learn even more about that topic, you can click on "more information." That will give you additional details using slightly more difficult words.

This information applies only to people who visit poki.com from the United Kingdom (UK). If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, please contact us at [privacy@poki.com](mailto:privacy@poki.com) or use our contact info below.

Click here for more information:

### Additional general information

Poki.com is owned and operated by Poki B.V. (referred to in this privacy statement as 'Poki', 'we', 'our', or 'us'). Poki is an entity incorporated under the laws of the Netherlands. This privacy statement ('Privacy Statement') is applicable to our primary website poki.com ('Website') as available from within the United Kingdom ('UK')\*.

_\* Please note that we determine from which region you visit our Website based on your IP-address, thus if you use a VPN-connection, you may not be shown the Privacy Statement applicable to you._

2\. Which parties use your data?
--------------------------------

We use your data to offer our website. We use the data to make the website work and to analyse how it's used. That way, we know what to improve. We do not share this data with other parties to use for their own purpose.

Poki.com is not just made possible by us. We work together with others. They are responsible for their use of your data. It concerns two types of parties: game developers and advertising partners. Game developers create the awesome games on our website. They sometimes use technologies such as so-called "cookies" to make their game work properly, or a similar technology. We will just keep calling it "cookies".

Advertising partners arrange for the advertisements (ads) you can see on our website. They sometimes also use cookies for this. Ads are images or movies to promote a product or service. The parties whose stuff is promoted, pay for the ads being shown. That's how we keep our website free for you.

Click here for more information:

### **Additional information on parties that use your data**

**Poki**. To ensure a privacy-friendly website for all our users ('Website Visitors') from the UK, Poki has created a privacy-friendly mode ('Privacy-Friendly Mode'). In the Privacy-Friendly Mode we do not collect and use data, other than certain technical and privacy-friendly analytical data. In the Privacy-Friendly Mode we only use cookies and similar technologies with no or very limited privacy impact. This concerns: functional cookies, first-party (privacy-friendly) analytical cookies and tag management systems only. For more information about what this means, please refer to section [5\. What about cookies](#section5).

**Games**. We do not make the games you can play on our website. These games are created by game developers. Game developers sometimes use cookies or similar technologies. For example, to track how much points you earned during a game. When they use cookies or your data for this, they should of course bear the privacy rules in mind. To ensure this, we have taken various steps. Firstly, we have agreements in place with the developers and inform them on their responsibilities. The developers of the games on the Website are in principle required to remove all outgoing links and branding/advertisements (e.g. splash-screens, social links and app-store links) from their game(s). They are only allowed to include cookies and similar technologies in their game if no consent for this is required under the applicable law. We've prepared [this list](https://poki.com/en/c/cookie-games) of the cookies used by our game developers, categorized per game, to inform you on behalf of the developers.\*

If developers do gather personal data for their own purposes, they are responsible for this, not Poki. Only the developer decides what (personal) data is processed and for what purpose. However, because Poki feels it is important that your data is also safe when you play a game, we took further measures. We actively search for cookies and similar technologies that developers may use which they shouldn't. If that occurs, we contact the developer and may decide to stop offering their game on (part) of our Website. Since we do not control their games, we cannot prevent every inappropriate cookie or similar technology. Therefore, if you notice something that makes you wonder, please let us know!

**Advertisements**. In the Privacy-Friendly Mode, no targeted advertisements are shown, also called "behavioural advertising". For behavioural advertising, the advertisements shown are based on your behaviour. For instance, if you clicked on an ad about a car on one website, another website may show you the same ad. On this UK Website, we do not use such behavioural ads. The ads shown on our UK Website are not based on any information we or others have about you. We only show non-personalized ads, suitable for all ages. These ads are "house ads" and/or "non-personalized ads" from third-parties. House ads are advertisements about other games available on the Poki Website, displayed by Poki. Non-personalized ads can be contextual ads. These ads are delivered based on the context - such as the game being played - instead of any information about you. The advertisers engaged are thoroughly vetted. The advertiser currently accepted for the UK will only serve ads under certain preconditions, including: (i) a tag for under the age of consent is included, as well as (ii) a tag for child-directed treatment. The tag "under the age of consent" means that the request is treated for users in the European Economic Area (EEA), the UK, and Switzerland for restricted data processing. According to the advertiser that uses this tag, it is designed to help facilitate compliance with the [General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679) and related child privacy regulations, such as the [Age Appropriate Design Code (AADC)](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/uk-gdpr-guidance-and-resources/childrens-information/childrens-code-guidance-and-resources/age-appropriate-design-a-code-of-practice-for-online-services/). The tag for child-directed treatment means that only ads appropriate for all ages are shown. The advertiser will then implement safeguards to prevent age-sensitive ad categories from being shown and will filter creatives based on its own policies.

**Externally hosted games, third party games and other websites.** This Privacy Statement does not apply to the processing of your data by data controllers other than Poki, such as providers of third-party games available on the Website. Poki is in no way responsible for cookies that are placed by and for other parties when you visit another webpage, also not if you are referred to such website from our Website. To enable you to make a conscious choice in this respect, we do include a banner if you play a game via our Website that is hosted on a third-party website. This banner informs you that you are about to access a third-party website. The relevant provider of such third-party game is responsible for ensuring that any processing of your data by them in the context of a game complies with the applicable data protection laws. In principle, Poki does not permit third-party content providers to collect personal data about Website Visitors. However, if any personal data will be collected by a third-party content provider, Poki will require that the processing of such data by them complies with the applicable law.

If you want to know more about any of the cookies used via our Website, the organizations we work with in this respect or have any other questions about this Privacy Statement, please feel free to contact us via [privacy@poki.com](mailto:privacy@poki.com).

_\* Please note that this list may not be complete, since randomized cookies that are placed with less than 100 Website Visitors are not included in the list. Furthermore, the cookies used by developers may change over time. Therefore, we automatically update this list daily._

3\. What data do we use and what for?
-------------------------------------

In Privacy-Friendly Mode, we try extra hard to use as little data as possible! That's why we don't use accounts, and why there's no chat-box. We collect the data we need to keep our website working and some privacy-friendly analytical data.

The main reason we use data is to make sure our website is safe and works well for you. We also use your data to save your game progress, so you can continue playing where you left off.

Analytical data helps us to count things, like how many people visited the website. Please note that we do not use any of this analytical information to build a profile or something. We don't have separate files available about an individual. We also do not use any of the data to treat you different. We just use it to analyse and improve our website in general. And to report to the developers about the statistics, such as how often their game was played.

Sometimes, we may also use data to handle requests, for legal reasons, or for security and control.

The personal data we use if you visit our website in Privacy-Friendly Mode, is included in the overview below. You see this overview if you click on "Data we use if you visit our website". If you want more information about what and why we collect (and some other legal stuff), click on "more information."

Data we use if you visit our website in Privacy-Friendly Mode

| Your data | Main reasons why we use it |
| --- | --- |
| IP address | This is a unique number. It's the number of the so-called computer network you use. We don't save this number. We only use this for your global geographic location (country-level, see below). |
| Session and user ID | This concerns the unique numbers we need to distinguish different users and sessions from one another. That way, we can for instance let developers know how many new people played their game that day. |
| Device type and screen specifics | We know what type of device you use and with what type of screen. We need this information to show the website and games in the right manner. You e.g. don't want a big game screen that doesn't fit on a smart phone. |
| Browser type | We know which type of browser you use (for example Chrome or Firefox). We need to know which browsers we need to support to make sure the games work in your browser. How it works in one browser is not always the same for another. |
| Country | We know in which country you are. We need this to ensure you see the right information for your country. |
| Other technical information | We also use other technical information to ensure that our website works properly, is secure and to analyse its usage. For example, information about the web pages that were visited, the links clicked and the log data. |

Sometimes, we use your data to handle requests or for legal reasons. The data we use if you contact us, is included in the overview below. You see this overview if you click on "Data we use if you contact us". If you want more information about what and why we collect (and some other legal stuff), click on "more information."

Data we use if you contact us

| Your personal data | Main reasons why we use it |
| --- | --- |
| Email address | We receive your email address if you send us a message on [hello@poki.com](mailto:hello@poki.com). |
| Phone number | If you ask us to contact you by phone, we use your phone number for this. |
| Name (if you provide one) | If you share your name with us, we will use it to respond to your questions or concern. |
| The message you sent or share with us | We will use your message to follow-up on for instance a bug that you told us about, or a question that you asked us. |
| Related metadata | If you send us a message, we will also use some technical data about the message. For instance, the date and time when you sent the message. We use this for security and to make sure we respond in time. The same applies if you call us. |

Click here for more information:

### 3.1 Which data is used and for what purposes?

All features on the Website are available without the need for registration. No personal data (such as e-mail addresses and phone numbers) are requested or processed, unless you actively contact us. Nonetheless, Poki does collect certain electronic data. We may process this data in various ways. Please find directly below some information about our processing of your data in general. Below the general processing purposes, you will find an overview of various topics on which you can click for more detailed information about the processing of your data in that context.

**General processing purposes**. In general, we may always process your data for the following purposes:

* For maintenance (including debugging), administration and network and security purposes;
* For internal control and business operations;
* For developing, analysing and improving the Website and our products;
* For handling any requests, complaints and disputes;
* For determining, exercising and defending our rights; and
* For complying with legal obligations (incl. fraud prevention) and requests of authorized governmental
institutions.

**Legitimate interest.** In the Privacy-Friendly Mode, we rely on the legal ground "legitimate interest". This means that a balance of interests is performed between the interests that are served by the processing on the one hand and your privacy interests on the other hand, and that the interests in favour of the processing prevail. The related legitimate interests are included below per topic. If you want more information about this, you can contact us directly via our contact details stated below.

**Legal obligation.** If we have a legal obligation to do so, we will process your data based on a legal obligation. In such case, we will store your data longer or separately from the data usage based on the legitimate interest. This means that we will process your data for as far as we are legally obliged to do so, for instance to comply with statutory minimum retention periods.

(i) Data we use if you visit our Website in Privacy-Friendly Mode

We process your data for providing, maintaining, analysing and improving the Website. We have specified this below.

| **The persons involved.** We process personal data of the following (categories of) people: | People who visit the Website (Website Visitors). |
| --- | --- |
| **The purpose of the processing.** When you visit the Website in Privacy-Friendly Mode, we will process your data for the following purposes: | * For our general processing purposes;<br>* For the functioning of the Website (incl. remembering your settings);<br>* For showing you the privacy information relevant to your region (which data we process exactly will depend on from which region you access the Website); and<br>* To provide our services to you and to technically deliver ads or content. |
| **The data that is processed.** When you visit the Website in Privacy-Friendly Mode, we may process the following information about you which is collected automatically: | * IP address;<br>* Session and user ID;<br>* Device type and screen specifics;<br>* Browser type;<br>* Country; and<br>* Other technical information. |
| **Legal grounds for the processing.** We base the use of your data in the context of the Website in Privacy-Friendly Mode on the following legal ground(s): | We base the use of your data in the context of the Website on the legitimate interest ground. It concerns our legitimate interest to secure, provide, analyse, and improve our services, as well as the developer's legitimate interest to obtain updates on the working and usage of their games in aggregated form. |

**Sensitive information.** In the context of the Website we do not purposefully process sensitive information, such as information about your health.

(ii) Data we use if you contact us

Poki may also process your personal data when you contact our support team.

| **The persons involved.** We process personal data of the following (categories of) people: | People who send an email to customer support, e.g. via [hello@poki.com](mailto:hello@poki.com) or [privacy@poki.com](mailto:privacy@poki.com), as well as people who call us or ask us to call them. |
| --- | --- |
| **The purpose of the processing.** When you contact Poki customer support or contact Poki otherwise, we will process your data for the following purposes: | * For our general processing purposes;<br>* To provide you with support;<br>* To fix the bug you informed us on; and<br>* To answer any questions you have for us or to respond to your concerns. |
| **The data that is processed.** When you contact Poki customer support or contact Poki otherwise, we will process the following information about you: | * Email address or phone number;<br>* Name (if you provide one);<br>* The message you sent or shared with us; and<br>* Related metadata. |
| **Legal grounds for the processing.** When you contact Poki customer support or contact Poki otherwise, we base the use of your data on the following legal ground(s): | We base the use of your data on the legitimate interest ground. It concerns our legitimate interest to provide you with support and answer any questions you have for us. Also, we refer to the other purposes mentioned above. |

4\. How do we get your data and who has access?
-----------------------------------------------

When you play games on our website, we automatically receive some information from you. We use a special thing called a "cookie" (not the tasty kind you eat) for this. The cookie collects the information. This for instance includes information on the type of device you use, in order to properly show you the game. You can learn more about cookies below!

We don't give your information to other people outside Poki to use for their own purposes. Within Poki, people only have access if they really need it. Only the people who need to use your data for their work, have access to it. For instance, some clever masterminds need your data to make sure everything runs smoothly. If something goes wrong, they fix it.

Sometimes, we ask other companies to help us with certain services. For example, a company might help us make our website really fast. We make sure these companies can be trusted and only use your data for our needs. We don't share your data in any other way. Other companies cannot use your data for their own purposes.

Remember, certain companies may collect your personal data themselves through our website for their own purposes. See section ["2. Which parties use your data?"](#section2) to learn more about this.

Click here for more information:

### 4.1 How do we receive your data?

Most data we obtain automatically via the Website, for example by using cookies and similar technologies. When your computer or mobile device contacts our web servers when you visit the Website, our web servers automatically collect usage information. For further information on cookies, please refer to section ["5. What about cookies"](#section5) below.

In some other cases we receive the data straight from you, for example when you send us a message via [hello@poki.com](mailto:hello@poki.com) or contact us via our website. In that case we receive the information you share with us directly from you. Certain data we do not receive directly but can be derived from the information already in our possession. For example, information about your language preferences.

Other (aggregated) information we use is no longer considered personal data, since this data is completely anonymized before we receive it. This means that we do not know to whom the data relates.

In exceptional circumstances, we may receive your data from a third-party. For example, if we receive information at the request of governmental institutions conducting an investigation.

In principle you are under no obligation to provide any information about yourself to us. However, refusal to supply certain information could have a negative influence on, for example, your experiences on or functionality of the Website. If the provision of certain personal data is a legal or contractual obligation or an essential requirement for concluding an agreement with us, we will separately provide additional information about this for as far as this is not clear in advance. In this case we will also inform you about the possible consequences if this information is not provided. In principle, this does not apply to the usage of our Website or if you contact us for support, questions or concerns.

### 4.2 Who do we share your data with?

We only share your data with third parties if:

* This is necessary for the provision of a service or the involvement of the third party. Sub-contractors, for example, will in principle only get access to the data that they require for their part of the service provision.
* The persons within the third-party that have access to the data are under an obligation to treat your data confidentially. Where necessary, this is also contractually agreed upon.
* The third-party is obliged to comply with the applicable regulations for the protection of personal data, for instance because we have concluded an agreement with this party. This means that the party is obligated to ensure appropriate technical and organizational security measures.

We could share your data on a need-to-know basis with the parties mentioned below. In this context, "need-to-know" means that a party only gets access to your data if and insofar as this is required for the professional services provided by this party.

* Poki personnel. Authorized persons, employed by Poki, who are involved with the processing activity concerned. Such as, the members of the support team you are in contact with.
* Personnel of our service providers. Authorized persons, employed by service providers/sub-contractors engaged by Poki, who are involved with the processing activity concerned. Such as, the service provider for Poki's internal processes.
* Authorized government institutions. Such as, courts, police, and law enforcement agencies. We may release information about our Website Visitors when we are legally required to do so, at the request of governmental institutions conducting an investigation or to verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing the Website and applicable laws. We may also disclose such user information whenever we believe disclosure is necessary to protect the rights, property or safety of Poki, or any of our respective business partners, customers or others.
* Aggregate Information. We may also disclose non-identifying, aggregated user statistics to third parties for a variety of purposes, including describing our services to prospective game developers. Examples of such non-personal information include the number of users who visited this Website during a specific time period or played a specific game.

5\. What about cookies?
-----------------------

We talked a little bit about cookies before, but let's dive deeper! The cookies we talk about are not the tasty kind 😉. Technical cookies are tiny bits of information, used on your computer or smartphone. When a cookie from our website is used on your device, it helps us to recognize you every time you visit our website. The cookie will "remember" you unless you delete it or if it stops working because it's expired. Thanks to cookies, we can "remember" your language settings, which games you played, and how far you've progressed in those games.

Some cookies are necessary for the website to work properly. If we can't use them, the website won't work either. Other cookies are used to count things. We want to know how many people visited the website and how many people played your favourite game! These cookies aren't scary at all. They don't gather information which we include in a "profile" or something. That's why we use them without you having to say "Okay!"

If you want to change your cookie settings in the Privacy-Friendly Mode, you can choose to block or delete them. But remember, if you delete our cookies, we won't be able to "remember" you anymore. And if you block our cookies, some parts of our website may not work.

You can delete or block our cookies using your browser's settings. Not sure how to do it? Just go to a search engine and type "how to block/delete cookies" along with the name of your browser, like Opera or Chrome. When you search, you'll find a step-by-step guide on how to do it. We've also included more information about this below!

Click here for more information:

Please [click here](https://poki.com/en/c/cookie-site) for an overview of cookies set by Poki. The overview includes information on the types and the names of the cookies, their purpose, what they are used for, whether it concerns a first or third-party cookie and the related validity period.

### 5.1 What are cookies?

**Cookies.** Cookies are small bits of data that can be placed on your computer, tablet, smartphone or other electronic "device" with which you can use the internet via a web browser. When a website is visited, the website can place these cookies on your device via your web browser. Examples of web browsers are: Microsoft Edge, Firefox, Safari, Google Chrome and Opera.

There are two different categories of cookies:

1. First party cookies. Cookies which Poki places on your device for its own purposes.
2. Third party cookies. Cookies placed by or for an external/third party (e.g. another company). On our Website it may concern cookies from game developers or advertising partners. This is explained above in section [“2. Which parties use your data?”](#section2).

**Purpose cookies.** After a cookie is placed on your device, your device can be recognized as you browse through the Website via the same web browser. This will for instance enable us to "remember" your language settings, which games you played and your progress in these games.

For more information on cookies, please refer to the website [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

**Lifecycle cookies.** After a cookie is placed on a device, it is only valid for a certain period.

1. Default period. After the validity period of a cookie passes, the cookie is automatically removed by the web browser. For local storage: Poki will make sure that the retention period is applied, as specified in the [Cookie Table](https://poki.com/en/c/cookie-site).
    
    The validity period varies per cookie. For example, some cookies are only valid during the browser session. Other cookies can also recognize your device if you visit the Website during a new browser session, e.g. for half a year after being placed.
    
2. Early deletion/refusal of cookies. You can choose to delete a cookie manually before its validity period has passed. For more information on this, please see the section below: "How can you manage cookies and cookie settings?".

**Similar technologies.** In addition to cookies, other techniques can also be used for similar purposes, such as tag management systems and HTML Local Storage. Tag management systems are used to enable consent-choices. HTML5 Local Storage and local shared objects can be used for the same purposes as cookies. Below, when we speak of "cookies", we also mean the similar technologies described above, unless we say otherwise.

### 5.2 What type of cookies do we use?

Poki uses two types of cookies on the Website: (i) functional cookies and (ii) analytical cookies. Developers and advertising partners may use their own cookies, as explained in section [“2. Which parties use your data?”](#section2) Developers may also use their own cookies. The developers of the games on the Website are in principle required to remove all outgoing links and branding/advertisements (e.g. splash-screens, social links and app-store links) from their game(s). They are only allowed to include cookies and similar technologies in their game if they abide by the local privacy rules. We've prepared [this list](https://poki.com/en/c/cookie-games) of the cookies used by our game developers, categorized per game, to inform you on behalf of the developers.\*

Advertising partners may also use cookies to show you advertisements. They are not allowed to show you targeted advertisements and need to abide by the privacy and e-privacy rules. More information on how they make sure of this, can be found in their own privacy documentation, such as [this information page](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads?hl=en-UK) on privacy advertising cookies from Google.

_\* Please note that this list may not be complete, since randomized cookies that are placed with less than 100 Website Visitors are not included in the list. Furthermore, the cookies used by developers may change over time. Therefore, we automatically update this list daily._

More information on the cookies we use ourselves, is provided below.

**(i) Functional cookies.**

Functional cookies are essential for the proper layout and navigation of a website. It concerns cookies (1) that are placed with the sole purpose of facilitating communication over an electronic communication network or (2) that are strictly necessary for providing you with the information-society service as requested by you.

**(ii) Analytical cookies.**

Analytical cookies are used to analyse the use of the Website, so that the quality and/or effectiveness of Poki’s services can be improved. For example, these cookies may help to detect design flaws and help us to provide aggregated information to the game developers. That way, game developers may for instance know how many people played their game on a certain day. If this number drops, they may wish to update or improve their game.

### 5.3 How can you manage cookies and cookie settings?

**Browser settings.** For most internet browsers it is possible to adjust the browser settings in such a way that you receive a warning before a cookie is placed. In most cases it is also possible to configure your browser to refuse all cookies or only third-party cookies. Furthermore, you can delete cookies which are already placed. Please keep in mind that it is necessary to adjust these settings separately on every different browser and computer you use.

**Functioning of the Website.** If you choose to block or delete certain cookies, it is possible (functions on) the Website do not work properly anymore. Deleting or refusing cookies also does not mean you will no longer see advertisements.

**How to change or delete cookie settings in your browser.** For your convenience, we have included links on how to change cookie settings on the most used internet browsers below:

**More information.** We care about security! Please consider carefully which web browser you use. Some browsers may benefit from sharing your personal data, while others are completely independent. We advise you to research the available web browsers and decide for yourself which browser best suits your interests. Please visit [www.whatismybrowser.com](http://www.whatismybrowser.com/) for information on the browser you use and more information on other browsers and browser settings.

6\. How about security?
-----------------------

Keeping your data safe is super important to us! We have done lots of things to make sure nothing bad happens to it. We have secret rules about security that only the people who work at Poki know about. These rules help us keep your data really safe! Everyone who works here is also trained to follow all the privacy rules. Also if something doesn't go according to plan.

Click here for more information:

**How do we secure your data?**

Protecting your privacy and data is very important to us. Therefore, Poki has implemented appropriate technical and organizational measures to protect and secure personal data, in order to prevent violations of the confidentiality, integrity and availability of the data. All Poki employees and other persons engaged by Poki for the processing of data are obliged to respect the confidentiality of personal data.

Poki has internal documentation which describes how we safeguard an appropriate level of technical and organizational security. In addition, a data breach procedure is applicable within Poki, which explains how (potential) data breaches need to be handled. We will, for example, inform the competent supervisory authority and the people involved when this is required by the applicable law.

7\. Is my data used in other countries?
---------------------------------------

Most likely, yes. We keep all our data in a country called the Netherlands (it's a really cool place, you should check it out!). If you visit our website from the United Kingdom, your data travels between your country and the Netherlands.

Sometimes, we need help with how we use your data. The parties we ask to help us, may not determine how to use your data. We give them instructions. We also check if their privacy info is in order. The company that helps us out with the secure storage of your data, is located outside the UK or EU. But they store the data for us in the Netherlands. The company that helps us out to make our website fast, is also based outside the UK or EU. Both companies have extensive info on so-called data transfers. They inform on how any transfer of personal data from the UK to outside the UK or the EU is allowed under the law.

Click here for more information:

**To which countries will we transfer your data?**

Poki stores your data in the Netherlands. For storing data, Poki uses BigQuery, a Google Cloud solution. The data is stored in the Netherlands. However, Google is headquartered in the US. How this relates to the transfer rules, is explained on [this webpage](https://policies.google.com/privacy/frameworks?hl=en).

Poki uses the data of CloudFlare to make the Website fast. How CloudFlare makes sure that the transfer rules are complied with, is explained on [this webpage](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/).

More generally, we can inform you as follows about the parties involved with the processing of your data originating from the UK. In case this data is transferred from the UK to outside the UK, the transfer is legitimized in the manner described below.

**Transfers outside the UK.** The transfer of your data from the UK to a third party outside the UK can in the first place be legitimized based on an adequacy regulation of the UK government. See [this link](https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/uk-approach-to-international-data-transfers/international-data-transfers-building-trust-delivering-growth-and-firing-up-innovation) for an overview of the applicable adequacy regulations.

If your personal data is transferred to a country outside the UK for which there is no adequacy decision or regulation in place, we agree on the applicability of the relevant version of the Standard Contractual Clauses with the relevant party. This is a standard contract to safeguard the protection of your data, which is approved by the European Commission in which the parties fill out the appendices. See [this link](https://commission.europa.eu/law/law-topic/data-protection/international-dimension-data-protection/standard-contractual-clauses-scc_en) for the various versions of the Standard Contractual Clauses. Where appropriate, additional safeguards should be taken. Since the UK General Data Protection Regulation ("UK GDPR") is applicable, the UK Addendum will also be applicable to the Standard Contractual Clauses mentioned above, as required by UK laws and regulations.

In specific situations we can also rely on the derogations from article 49 UK GDPR to legitimize the data transfer. This means that we may transfer your data: (i) with your explicit consent, (ii) if this is necessary for the performance of a contract that has been concluded with you or has been concluded in your interest, or (iii) if this is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. Lastly, in exceptional cases we may also transfer your data if the data transfer is necessary for our compelling legitimate interests and is not overridden by your interests or rights and freedoms.

You can contact us if you want additional information about the way in which we legitimize the transfer of your data to countries outside the UK. Our contact details are stated at the bottom of this Privacy Statement.

**Google Analytics Blockage.** Please note that we do not use Google Analytics on our Website for the UK. However, it is possible that one of the game developers we work with tries to use Google Analytics for tracking in-game activities. We actively try to find these implementations and overwrite them. Thus, if you visit our Website, your data should not be shared with Google for Google Analytics.

8\. For how long do you use my data?
------------------------------------

The cookies we use expire after up to six months. But remember, this period may be extended. If you come back to our website within six months, the six-month period starts over again. If you do not want that, you can delete your cookies.

After a cookie is deleted or expired, we no longer know to whom the cookie data relates. For more info on our retention policy, please see below.

Click here for more information:

**How do we determine how long we retain your data?**

In general, we do not keep your data for longer than what is necessary in relation to the purposes for which we process the data. There could however be exceptions applicable to the general retention terms. The cookies we use expire after up to six months, without intermediate renewals. Poki can only “remember” a user during the validity period of a cookie. If cookies expire or are deleted, Poki can no longer determine to whom that information belongs. The six-month period restarts if you revisit the Website within six months without deleting our cookies. For info on how to delete cookies, please see section ["5.3 How can you manage cookies and cookie settings?"](#section53).

**Exception: shorter retention period.** If you exercise certain privacy rights, it is possible that Poki will remove your data earlier than the general applicable retention period or - oppositely - retain it for a longer period of time. For more information about this, please refer to the header "What are your privacy rights (incl. the right to object)?". Also, if you delete your cookies we can no longer recognize you from your previous visits.

**Exception: longer retention period.** In certain situations, we process your data for a longer period of time than what is necessary for the purpose of the processing. This is for instance the case when we have to process your data for a longer period of time:

* **Retention obligation.** To comply with a minimum retention period or other legal obligation to which we are subject based on the applicable law;
* **Procedure.** Your personal data is necessary in relation to a legal procedure;
* **Freedom of expression.** When further processing of your personal data is necessary in order to exercise the right to freedom of expression and information.

9\. What are my rights?
-----------------------

You can always ask what information we have about you. If you want, you can also ask us to delete your information or just keep it without using it anymore. If you think something is wrong with the information we have, you can ask us to fix it.

We don't use your information to create a profile or make decisions about you, but if we did, we would tell you. If you ever think we're not following the rules, you can tell the authorities (that's sort of the government). You can ask a grown-up to help you with this or ask us directly.

If you want to talk to us about any of these things, send us a message via the contact information below.

Click here for more information:

### 9.1 What are your privacy rights (incl. right to object)?

Based on the UK GDPR you have various privacy rights. To what extent you can exercise these rights may depend on the circumstances of the processing, such as the manner in which Poki processes the personal data and the legal basis for the processing. Below, we included a summary of your privacy rights under the UK GDPR. For more information about your privacy rights, visit [this webpage](https://ico.org.uk/your-data-matters/) of the UK Information Commissioner's Office.

We will respond to all requests without undue delay. If our full response will ever take more than a month due to complexity or number of requests, we will notify you of this and keep you updated. Furthermore, please note that we may request more information to confirm your identity before acting on any request.

### 9.2 Your privacy rights.

In relation to our processing of your personal data, you have the following privacy rights.

1. **Right to withdraw consent.** In so far as our processing of your data is based on your consent, you have the right to withdraw your consent. Please note that in the Privacy-Friendly Mode, Poki does not base the processing of your data via the Website on your consent.
    
    If we obtain consent in another context, please note the following. Withdrawal of consent does not influence the legitimacy of the processing before you withdrew your consent. If you withdraw your consent, Poki will no longer process your data for the purpose that you consented to. It can however be possible that we still process the personal data for another purpose, such as to comply with a minimum retention period. In that case you will be informed about this.
    
2. **Right of access.** You have the right to request access to your data. This enables you to receive a copy of the data we hold about you (but not necessarily the documents themselves). We will then also provide you with further specifics of our processing of your personal data. For example, the purposes for which we process your data, where we got it from, and with whom we share it.
3. **Right to rectification.** You have the right to request rectification of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected. You have this right in case we process personal data about you that: (i) is factually incorrect; (ii) is incomplete or not related to the purpose it was collected for; or (iii) is in any other way used in a manner that is in conflict with an applicable law. The right of rectification is not intended for the correction of professional opinions, findings or conclusions that you do not agree with. However, Poki could in such case consider adding your opinion about this to your data.
    
    Since we mainly process technical data, we are often not able to rectify your personal data. If the computer recorded that you accessed our Website at 15:12h UK time, we cannot just change this in our records. If we are unable to rectify your data, we can offer you the option of deleting it instead.
    
4. **Right to erasure.** You have the right to request erasure of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove your data where: (i) the data is no longer necessary, (ii) you have withdrawn your consent, (iii) you have objected to the processing activities, (iv) the data has been unlawfully processed, (v) the data has to be erased on the basis of a legal requirement, or (vi) where the data has been collected in relation to the offer of information society services.
    
    However, we do not have to honour your request to the extent that the processing is necessary: (i) for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information, (ii) for compliance with a legal obligation which requires processing, (iii) for reasons of public interest in the area of public health, (iv) for archiving purposes, or (v) for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.
    
5. **Right to object.** You have the right to object to the processing of your data where we are relying on legitimate interest as processing ground (see above). Insofar as the processing of your data takes place for direct marketing purposes, we will always honour your request. For processing for other purposes, we will also cease and desist processing, unless we have compelling legitimate grounds which override your interests, rights and freedoms or that are related to the institution, exercise or substantiation of a legal claim. If such is the case, we will inform you on our compelling grounds and the balance of interests made. Outside the Privacy-Friendly Mode, you can also decide to refuse the cookies which may only be used with your consent. For more information on this, please see section ["5.3 How can you manage cookies and cookie settings?"](#section53).
6. **Right to restriction.** The right to restriction of processing means that Poki will continue to store personal data at your request but may in principle not do anything further with it. In short, you have this right when Poki does not have (or no longer has) any legal grounds for the processing of your data or if this is under discussion. This right is specifically applicable in the following situations:
    
    1. **Unlawful processing.** We may not (or no longer) process certain personal data, but you do not want us to erase the data. For example, because you still want to request the data at a later stage.
        
    2. **Data no longer required.** Poki no longer needs your data for our processing purposes, but you still require the personal data for a legal claim. For example, in case of a dispute.
        
    3. **Pending an appeal.** You objected against the processing of your data by Poki (see the right to object above). Pending the verification of your appeal we shall no longer process this personal data at your request.
        
    4. **Contesting the accuracy of data.** You contest the accuracy of certain data that we process about you (e.g. via your right to rectification; see above). During the period in which we assess your contest we shall no longer process this personal data at your request.
        
7. **Right to data portability.** You have the right to request the transfer of your data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format to you or to a third party of your choice (right to data portability). Please note that this right only applies if it concerns processing that is carried out by us by automated means, and only if our processing ground for such processing is your consent or the performance of a contract to which you are a party (see above). For the Privacy-Friendly Mode, Poki does not base the processing of your data via the Website on consent or the performance of a contract.
8. **Automated decision-making.** You have the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, which significantly impacts you ("which produces legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affects you"). In this respect, please be informed that when processing your personal data, we do not make use of automated decision-making which significantly impacts you.
9. **Right to complaint.** In addition to the above-mentioned rights, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the UK, your place of work or where an alleged infringement took place. Please refer to [this webpage](https://ico.org.uk/) for the supervisory authority in the UK. However, we would appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach any supervisory authority, so please contact us beforehand.

### 9.3 How to exercise your rights.

You can exercise your privacy rights free of charge, by phone or by e-mail via the contact details displayed below. If requests are manifestly unfounded or excessive, in particular because of the repetitive character, we will either charge you a reasonable fee or refuse to comply with the request.

Please note that if your request concerns data we obtained via cookies, you will also need to share certain cookie information with us. We need this data to determine which part of the data we hold, relates to you. No need to worry about how you will obtain this cookie information. If you contact us, we will inform you on how you can obtain and share the necessary information with us.

### 9.4 Verification of your identity.

We may request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity before we further respond to your privacy request.

### 9.5 Follow-up of your requests.

Follow-up of your requests. We will provide you with information about the follow-up of the request without undue delay and in principle within one month of receipt of the request. Depending on the complexity of the request and on the number of requests, this period can be extended by another two months. We will notify you of such an extension within one month of receipt of the request. The applicable (privacy) legislation may allow or require us to refuse your request. If we cannot comply with your request, we will inform you of the reasons why, subject to any legal or regulatory restrictions.

10\. How can you contact us?
----------------------------

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement or about how we use your data, please contact us at [privacy@poki.com](mailto:privacy@poki.com) or via:

Poki B.V.  
Spui 10  
1012 WZ Amsterdam  
The Netherlands  
+31 20 2800 870 (for communication in Dutch or English)

If you want to talk to us on the phone in a different language, please send us an e-mail first and let us know. We'll give you the right phone number so we can talk in the language you prefer.

11\. Changes
------------

Sometimes we need to update this Privacy Statement to keep up with new things like technology or rules. You can always check the latest version on our website. If there are any big changes that you need to know about, we will also let you know.

Let the world play

⚙️ Cookies[About](https://about.poki.com/)[Poki for Developers](https://developers.poki.com/)[Jobs](https://jobs.poki.com/)[Privacy Statement](https://poki.com/en/c/privacy-statement)[Terms of Use](https://poki.com/en/c/terms-of-use)[FAQ](https://poki.com/en/c/faq)[Contact](https://poki.com/en/c/contact)

Poki v5.12.0+29bedb4acf8dafb63c9407897f25591326e2b507 - SDK 372d1d2fb397343a240619df4558e76734e4d551
